Ben Shaktman Papers
Ben Shaktman Papers
1949-2009
Shaktman, Ben, 1937-
54 linear feet
Papers of the American playwright and director. Correspondence subject files; production material comprising research, notes, costume sketches, and drafts for plays by Bertolt Brecht, Eugene O'Neill, Arnold Wesker, Ben Shaktman and others; manuscripts; printed material (posters, playbills, programs, more); audiovisual material including audiotapes, photographs; material pertaining to Royal Court Theater in London, The Berliner Ensemble, Pittsburgh Public Theater (PPT), Theatre Nationale Populaire (TNP) in Paris, The National Endowment for the Arts; more
149577
Biographical History
Ben Shaktman (1937- ) is an American playwright and director of Off-Broadway, regional repertory and television productions. He also created Shaktman Associates, an executive skills training company.
Shaktman was born in Peabody, Massachusetts in 1937. His given first name was Bernard which he changed to Ben in 1960. He received his B.A. degree Magna Cum Laude from Syracuse University in 1959 and his M. A. degree in social science from the Maxwell School of Political Science at Syracuse University in 1964.
Upon receiving a Fulbright fellowship (1959-1961) in playwriting and subsequently in directing, Shaktman went to Europe where he studied and worked at Oxford, Bristol University, the University of London, Paris, and Berlin. He was an observing director at the Royal Court Theater in London, and at the Theatre Nationale Populaire (TNP) in Paris, he co-directed Bertolt Brecht's Les Fusils de Señora Carrar in 1961. He worked as a directorial associate at the Berliner Ensemble which at that time was in East Berlin, assisting in the staging of Ostrovsky's The Abyss. His own play, Point in the Square, was produced in 1960 by the Bristol Old Vic School.
After returning to the United States in 1962, Shaktman served for two years as artist-in-residence and lecturer in drama at Syracuse University. While at Syracuse he staged the U.S. premiere of Bertolt Brecht's The Guns of Carrar, with a new translation by George Tabori.
In 1964 he spent a year at the Charles Playhouse in Boston collaborating with poet Anne Sexton in the development of her first play, which at the time had a working title of Give Me Your Answer (Do Daisy) (the final title was Tell Me Your Answer True). He also staged the musical She Loves Me, and created a unique musical theater for children, with musical director Joe Raposo, which toured schools in the greater Boston area.
In 1975 Shaktman was one of the founders of the Pittsburgh Public Theater where he served as general and artistic director until 1982. During that time he was responsible for establishing the theater's financial and artistic foundations and directed a majority of productions during PPT's first seven years.
In 1983 Shaktman expanded the application of his theatrical and directorial skills to the business world when he became the founder and president of Shaktman Associates, an executive consulting and training firm. It trains and coaches corporate executives, teachers, professors, and community leaders in the effective preparation and delivery of presentations. (See separate collection,
Shaktman Associates Records
.) He continues as its president today (2015).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Ben Shaktman Papers spans the years 1949-2009 and is divided into six groups: Biographical material, Correspondence/subject files, Productions directed by Shaktman, Productions involving Shaktman, Productions proposed by Shaktman, Writings, and Memorabilia.
Biographical material contains a biographical article, typewrittten biography and c.v. with notes and corrections by Mr. Shaktman, plus his passport.
Correspondence/subject files is arranged alphabetically and includes letters to and from actors, agents, playwrights and other members of the theatrical community as well as personal correspondence.
Productions directed by Shaktman comprises materials relating to the production of the plays for which Ben Shaktman was the principle director.
Productions involving Shaktman comprises materials relating to the production of the plays for which Ben Shaktman was in some other role than principle director. The bulk of the material is from Pittsburgh Public Theater during the years he was General Director of the company.
Productions proposed by Shaktman comprises materials relating to the production he proposed that were either not produced or were produced by others.
All productions are arranged alphabetically by title. Correspondence dealing directly with a particular production has been arranged chronologically and placed under the play with which it is concerned. Some larger photographs as well as costume sketches for "The Emperor Jones," are located in the oversize packages at the end of the collection.
Writings is divided into the following sections: Adaptations of others' work; Articles and essays; Books; Lectures and courses; Letters to the editor; Lyrics; Pamphlets; Personal journals; Plays; Poetry; Program notes; Reviews; Screeplays; Television series and specials and Thesis (material collected by him for a study of the Negro actor on the legitimate stage done at Syracuse University). the thesis material is arranged alphabetically by section titles given by Mr. Shaktman.
Memorabilia is divided into the following sections: Address books and calendars; Clippings; Event programs(many of which include Shaktman's marginal notes); Phone messages;Photographs; Printed material; Pittsburgh Public Theater; Posters; Postcards; Scrapbook; scheduling planners; and Travel souvenirs.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically by type or title.
Related Material
has a large number of collections relating to theatre and drama; please refer to for a complete listing.
Separated Material
Published books have been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to and search on the phrase "Gift of Ben Shaktman" for a complete listing.
As part of the complete reprocessing in March 2012, material relating to Shaktman Associates was removed and processed as a separate collection., the
Shaktman Associates Records
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Dance and theatre; Popular culture; Alexander, Jane, 1939-; Anderson, Lindsay, 1923-1994.; Arden, John.; Bancroft, Anne, 1931-2005.; Barnes, Clive, 1927-2008.; Baxter, Anne.; Bellantoni, Patti.; Bellon, Jacquie.; Bochco, Steven, 1943-; Boorstein, Joan.; Booth, Susan V.; Borenstein, Joyce.; Bosakowski, Phil.; Bottner, Barbara.; Brecht, Bertolt, 1898-1956.; Brooks, Gwendolyn, 1917-2000.; Brown, Arvin.; Caliguiri, Richard S.; Carden, William.; Case, Bertha.; Castang, Veronica, 1938-1988.; Cates, Gilbert, 1934-2011.; Cheskin, Irving.; Clay, Buriel, 1943-1978.; Copeland, James, 1923-; Copelin, David.; Cronyn, Hume.; Crosby, Kathryn, 1933-; Croyden, Joan.; Cutrona, Ryan.; Davidson, Gordon, 1933-; Davis, Sammy, 1925-1990.; Goldschmidt, Gilbert de.; Devine, George, 1910-1966.; Dillingham, Charles.; Dodson, Owen, 1914-1983.; Duberman, Martin B.; Duke, Patty, 1946-2016.; Dunster, Claude.; Empleton, Elizabeth.; Fichandler, Zelda, 1924-; Flaherty, Peter F., 1924-; Fosse, Bob, 1927-1987.; Funt, Allen, 1914-1999.; Gaines, William Louis.; Garcia, Andy.; Gister, Earle R., 1934-; Going, John.; Golden, Joseph, 1928-; Grossman, Milton M.; Guettel, Hank.; Guthrie, Tyrone, Sir, 1900-1971.; Handman, Wynn.; Hankin, Larry.; Harris, Berkeley.; Hart, Bruce.; Hart, Lou S.; Hellman, Lillian, 1905-1984.; Henson, Jim.; Heriza, Nirmala, 1946-; Hesseltine, Stark.; Howard, Pamela, 1939-; Irving, Jules, 1925-; Jones, James Earl.; Jones, Welton.; Kahn-Leavitt, Laurie.; Kalfin, Robert.; Kastelas, Milton.; Langella, Frank.; Levinson, Aaron.; Lithgow, John, 1945-; Litz, Robert J.; Lorant, Stefan, 1901-1997.; Lovelace, Margo.; Ludden, Allen.; MacDermot, Galt.; Markson, Edith Sherin.; Medencevic, Suki.; Michlin, Barry.; Miner, Worthington, 1900-1982.; Moore, Dudley, 1935-2002.; Movsesian, Nance.; Nagrin, Daniel.; Neijna, Barbara.; Neipris-Wille, Janet.; Newberry, Greg.; Newman, Danny.; Nimoy, Leonard.; Noel, Craig.; Noonan, John Ford.; Norton, Elliot, 1903-; Oates, Joyce Carol, 1938-; Obadiah, Rick.; O'Bannon, Helen B., 1939-1988.; Obolensky, Kira.; O'Casey, Eileen.; Olivier, Laurence, 1907-1989.; O'Neill, Carlotta.; Padula, Edward, 1916-2001.; Pagano, Rich.; Passeltiner, Bernie.; Piskor, Frank Peter.; Poitier, Sidney.; Polis, Joel.; Pons, Beatrice Moore.; Posvar, Wesley.; Prince, Harold, 1928-; Raposo, Joe.; Rayvid, Jay.; Reidenbaugh, Gerald F.; Rich, David Lowell.; Ridley, Clifford A.; Robbins, Jerome.; Rogers, Fred.; Rosenak, David.; Ruscio, Michael.; Schell, Ina.; Schoenfeld, Gerald, 1924-2008.; Schreiber, Terry.; Sexton, Anne, 1928-1974.; Shaktman, Ben, 1937-; Shaw, Roy, 1936-2012.; Sileika, Gintare.; Silverman, Fred, 1937-; Soble, Lisa-Marie.; Solvang, Tobi.; Sondheim, Stephen.; Strauch, Barbara.; Strickland, William E., Jr.; Strouse, Charles.; Swoyer, Julia.; Tabori, George, 1914-2007.; Tagg, Alan.; Thornburgh, Dick.; Toser, David.; Tutera, Cindy.; Vestoff, Virginia.; Wakefield, Yanoulla.; Waley, Arthur.; Wanamaker, Sam, 1919-1993.; Weil, Marian J.; Weiswiller, Carole.; Weitzman, Lew.; Wesker, Arnold, 1932-2016.; Wilcox, Kay.; Wilder, Isabel, 1900-1995.; Wolsk, Eugene V.; Zabusky, Charlotte Fox.; Zeisler, Peter.; Zulia, Ernest.; TACT, The Actors Company Theatre.; Actors' Equity Association.; American Academy of Dramatic Arts.; Berliner Ensemble.; Carnegie-Mellon University.; The Charles Playhouse.; Chesterfield Writers' Project.; Cincinnati Playhouse in the Park.; City Theatre, Pittsburgh.; Directors Guild of America.; The Eugene O'Neill Theater Center.; George Washington University.; Humana Festival.; Los Angeles Independent Film Festival.; MTV Networks.; National Endowment for the Arts -- Theater Program.; North Shore Music Theatre.; Pennsylvania Council on the Arts.; Pittsburgh Public Theater.; The Pythons.; Syracuse University.; University of California, Los Angeles. -- School of Theater, Film and Television.; Universal City Studios.; University of Pittsburgh.; Warner Bros.; Yale University.; Acting -- Study and teaching.; African Americans in the performing arts.; Musicals -- Production and direction.; Television -- Production and direction.; Theater -- Production and direction.; Audiotapes.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Drafts (documents); Lecture notes.; Photographs.; Research notes.; Reviews (documents); Scripts (documents); Sketches.; Slides (photographs); Theater programs.; Directors.; Dramatists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ben Shaktman, 1966, 1968, 1971, 1978, 1980, 1982, 1984, 1986, 1987, 1989, 1991-1998, 2000, 2001, 2003, 2004, 2006-2009.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Article, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Biographical sketch, 1975-1982 (Box 1)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1975-1982 (Box 1)
  - Passport (Box 1)
- Correspondence Subject Files
  - AA-AL (Box 2)
  - AM-AV (Box 2)
  - The Actors Company Theatre, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Actors' Equity Association, 1965-1981 (Box 2)
  - Adam, Nancy, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Adams, Beth, 1978-1981 (Box 2)
  - Adler, Pam, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Alexander, Jane, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Alexander, Robert, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Alexander, Wayne, 1992-1996 (Box 2)
  - Alford, Walter, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Allmanrae, Didi, 1978; 2003,; 2004,; 2007 (Box 2)
  - Altshuler, Evelyn, 1971; 1989-2006 (Box 2)
  - American Academy of Dramatic Arts, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - American Cinematheque, 1995 (Box 2)
  - American Conservatory Theatre of San Francisco, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - American Film Market Seminars, 1996-1998 (Box 2)
  - American Symphony Orchestra League, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Amitin, Nancy, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Anderson, George, 1978; 1982,; 1992 (Box 3)
  - Anderson, Lindsay, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Angelou, Angel, 1992-2005 (Box 3)
  - Apt, Joan, 1973-2003 (Box 3)
  - Arden, John, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Arizona Theatre Company, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Arkin, Jonathan, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Arthurs, Alberta, See Chatham College and The Rockefeller Foundation. (Box 3)
  - Askestig, Erika, 1992-2005 (Box 3)
  - Astin, Art and Jeane, 1990-2005 (Box 3)
  - Atkins, Tom, 1975-1978 (Box 3)
  - Ausman, Sandra and Sheldon, 1975-1983 (Box 3)
  - BA-BL (Box 3)
  - BO-BU (Box 3)
  - Backes, Roy, 1980-1983 (Box 3)
  - Baker, Nancy, 1978-1996 (Box 3)
  - Ball, Bill, See American Conservatory Theatre of San Francisco.
  - Bancroft, Anne, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Barnes, Clive, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Barr, Richard, 1966; 1970 (Box 3)
  - Barranger, Milly, 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - Barry, P.J., 1994 (Box 3)
  - Bassuk, Ellen and Steve, 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Baxter, Anne, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Behrman, S. N., 1972 (Box 4)
  - Bellantoni, Patti, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Bellon, Jacquie, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Benson, Jay, See Universal City Studios.
  - Berger, Ira M., 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Berger, Lisa, See MTV Networks.
  - Berliner Ensemble, 1956-1960; undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Berliner Ensemble photographs (Oversize 1)
  - Biro, Samantha, 1979-1995; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Bochco, Steven, 1972-1983 (Box 5)
  - Boorstein, Joan, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Booth, Susan, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Borenstein, Joyce, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
  - Bosakowski, Philip, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Bottner, Barbara, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Brandt, George W., 1963; 1981 (Box 5)
  - Brannigan, Bernard and Carol, 1986-1992 (Box 5)
  - Brecht, Bertolt, 1960; undated (Box 5)
  - Brooks, Gwendolyn, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Brown, Arvin, 1987; 1996 (Box 5)
  - Bundy, Barbara, 1973-1974; 1977 (Box 5)
  - Burlingame, Ed, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Butler, Robert, See White Mile Workshop.
  - C-CL (Box 5)
  - CO-CU (Box 5)
  - California Lawyers For The Arts Workshop, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Caliguiri, Richard S., 1979; 1981 (Box 5)
  - Camillo, Mary Ann, 1967; 1982-1987 (Box 5)
  - Cancelino, Sally, 1979-1981 (Box 5)
  - Caprile, Marie, 1983-1986 (Box 6)
  - Carden, William, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Carnahan, Peter, See Pennsylvania Council on the Arts.
  - Carnegie Institute Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1974; 1977 (Box 6)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University, 1973-1977; 1993,; 1997 (Box 6)
  - Carpenter, John, 1981-1983 (Box 6)
  - Case, Bertha, 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Castang, Veronica, 1976-1980 (Box 6)
  - Cates, Gilbert, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Center Theatre Group, 1996; See also Davidson, Gordon. (Box 6)
  - Chaffon, V., 1981-1987 (Box 6)
  - The Charles Playhouse, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Chatham College, 1976-1978 (Box 6)
  - Cheskin, Irving, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Chesterfield Writers' Project, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Chotzinoff, Kris and Blair, 1973-1986 (Box 6)
  - Cincinnati Playhouse in the Park, 1996 (Box 6)
  - City of Lights, City of Angels: A Week of French Films, 1999 (Box 6)
  - City Theatre, Pittsburgh, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Clay Buriel III, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Cohen, Alexander H., 1965; 1967,; 1974-1975,; 1981 (Box 6)
  - Cold Spring Film Workshop, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Cole, Toby, 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Contacts, 1995-2000 (Box 6)
  - Copeland, James, 1977-1980 (Box 6)
  - Copelin, David, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Corbett, Anne, 1966-1967; 1986 (Box 6)
  - Cornell, Mark W., 1996 (Box 6)
  - Cowles, Arthur W., 1975; 1987 (Box 6)
  - Craig, Jackie L., 1986-1987 (Box 6)
  - Cronyn, Hume, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Crosby, Kathryn, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
  - Croyden, Joan, 1976; 1978 (Box 7)
  - Cutrona, Ryan, 1991 (Box 7)
  - D (Box 7)
  - Dane, Ann, 1980-1983 (Box 7)
  - Dane, Barbara (Mrs John Hunter Dane), 1974-1976; 1979-1981 (Box 7)
  - Davidson, Gordon, 1966; 1971,; 1973-1981,; 1990,; 1992,; 1996 (Box 7)
  - Davidson, John and Inga, 1975-1976; 1978 (Box 7)
  - Davis, Sammy, Jr., 1962 (Box 7)
  - DeCarlo, Charles R., 1972-1976; 1987,; 2005 (Box 7)
  - Devine, George, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Diamondstone, Nathlyn, 1995-1999 (Box 7)
  - Digital Visual Effects, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Dillingham, Charles, 1972; 1981 (Box 7)
  - Directors Guild of America, 1970; 1981,; 1987-1997 (Box 7)
  - The Director's Notebook Workshop, 1993 (Box 8)
  - The Director's Perspective on Filmmaking BAFTA Seminar UCLA, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Dodson, Owen, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Dretzin and Kauff, 1981-1983 (Box 8)
  - Duberman, Martin, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Duke, Patty, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Dunn, Susan L., 1981-1982 (Box 8)
  - Dunster, Mark ("Claude"), 1967 (Box 8)
  - E (Box 8)
  - Eddy, Edward D., See Chatham College.
  - Effron, Jill, 2000-2007 (Box 8)
  - Eils, Nancy, 1991-2002 (Box 8)
  - Eismen, Audrey, 1977-1979; 1983,; 1985 (Box 8)
  - Elderman, Edward, 2002-2004 (Box 8)
  - Eliasberg, Jan, 1983-1985; 1991 (Box 8)
  - Ellsworth, Ellie, 1984; 1992-1995 (Box 8)
  - Empleton, Elizabeth, 1989-1992 (Box 8)
  - Engel, Susan, 1982; 1987 (Box 8)
  - Epstein, David, 1997 (Box 8)
  - Epstein, Jon, See Universal City Studios.
  - The Eugene O'Neill Theater Center, 1989-1997 (Box 9)
  - Europe, 1982-1987 (Box 9)
  - F (Box 9)
  - Fichandler, Zelda, 1971; 1978-1979,; 1982,; 1987,; 1995,; 1997 (Box 9)
  - First American Congress of Theatre, 1976 (Box 9)
  - First Comics, Inc, See Obadiah, Rick.
  - Flaherty, Pete, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Flanagan, Michael, 1975-1978 (Box 9)
  - Fleischman, Stephanie, 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Forbes, Jan, 1976-1981; 1990-1993,; 2000,; 2002 (Box 9)
  - Fosse, Bob, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Frand, Harvey, See Warner Brothers Studio.
  - Friedman, Lauren (Lauren Shaktman), 1966-1972; 1995,; 1998,; 2005 (Box 9)
  - Friedman, Samuel E., 1971 (Box 9)
  - Funt, Allen A., 1970 (Box 9)
  - G - GL (Box 10)
  - GO - GY (Box 10)
  - Gaines, William Louis, 1963-1968; 1978 (Box 10)
  - Garcia, Andy, undated (Box 10)
  - Garver, Richard, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Gauri, Indra, 1994 (Box 10)
  - George Washington University, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Gibeley, Albert, 1967 (Box 10)
  - Giovanetti, Clara, 1997-1998; 2006 (Box 10)
  - Gister, Earle R., 1975; 1982-1983 (Box 10)
  - Going, John, 1975-2005; 2007 (Box 10)
  - Golden, Joe, 1964-1966 (Box 10)
  - Goldschmidt, Gilbert de, 1984-1987 (Box 10)
  - Grabie, Morris, 1991; 2002 (Box 10)
  - Grossman, Anne ("Cookie") and Elizabeth ("Lisa"), 1971-2005; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Grossman, Milton M., 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Groth, Michael J., 2003 (Box 11)
  - Guettel, Henry, 1966
  - Guthrie, Tyrone, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Gwathmey, Annie, 1999-2003 (Box 11)
  - Gwathmey, Emily, 1999-2006; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - H (Box 11)
  - Hadaller, Carrie, 1996 (Box 11)
  - Hahn, Richard, 1994 (Box 12)
  - Hainesworth, Margaret, 1985 (Box 12)
  - Halpern, Sophye, 1968-2003; 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Handman, Wynn, 1964 (Box 12)
  - Hankin, Larry, 1990; See also "Emmet Sez". (Box 12)
  - Hanks, Nancy, 1976; 1983 (Box 12)
  - Hannigan, Patricia, 1976-1978 (Box 12)
  - Harris, Audrey, 1976 (Box 12)
  - Harris, Berkeley, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Hart, Bruce and Carole, 1964-2006; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Hart, Lou S., 1964; 1970,; 1981 (Box 13)
  - Havardi, Raz, 1999 (Box 13)
  - Heim, Michael, 1976-1982; 1990 (Box 13)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Hemlock Society, 1994 (Box 13)
  - Henson, Jim, 1983 (Box 13)
  - Heriza, Nirmala, 1991; 1998-2005 (Box 13)
  - Hesseltine, Stark, 1966-1975 (Box 13)
  - Hettleman, Bertha, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Hill, Carol, 1966-1967 (Box 13)
  - Hollister, Jo Ann, 1990 (Box 13)
  - Homas, Mary, 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Houghton, Katherine, 1976-1987 (Box 13)
  - Howard, Pamela, 1975; 1983-1984,; 1987 (Box 13)
  - Howe, Tina, 1981-1982 (Box 13)
  - Hughes, Tressa, 1973; 1975,; 1977,; 1986-1987 (Box 14)
  - Hulton, Christine, 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - Human Relations Workshop Syracuse University, 1963 (Box 14)
  - Humana Festival of New American Plays, 1996 (Box 14)
  - Humana Festival of New American Plays, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Hunt, Alfred M., 1977; 1983 (Box 14)
  - Hunt, Marion, 1986 (Box 14)
  - I - J (Box 14)
  - Institute For The Preservation Of The Original Languages Of The Americas, 1993 (Box 14)
  - International Documentary Association, 1992-1995; 2 folders of 3 (Box 14)
  - International Documentary Association, 1992-1995; 1 folder of 3 (Box 15)
  - Irving, Jules, 1967; 1973 (Box 15)
  - Jacker, Corinne, 1995 (Box 15)
  - Jenkins, Carol Mayo, 1971-1975 (Box 15)
  - Jensen, John, 1976-1978 (Box 15)
  - Job prospects, 1982-1983 (Box 15)
  - Jonas, Judy, 1995 (Box 15)
  - Jones, James Earl, 1972; 1977,; 1988-1989 (Box 15)
  - Jones, Welton, 1981 (Box 15)
  - K (Box 15)
  - Kahn-Leavitt, Laurie, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Kandrack, Lucille, 1982-1983 (Box 15)
  - Kalfin, Robert, 1974-1976 (Box 15)
  - Kaplan, Morris, 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Kastelas, Milton, 1975 (Box 15)
  - Kauff, Jerome B., 1972-1975; 1979,; 1983 (Box 15)
  - Kelson, Ellen, 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - Kennedy, Canice, 1976-1981 (Box 15)
  - Kennedy, Ellen, 1977-1993 (Box 15)
  - Kennedy, John J., Jr., 1981-1990 (Box 15)
  - Kerr, Elaine, 1977-1978; 1983 (Box 15)
  - Kerr, Michael, 1983 (Box 15)
  - King, Woodie, Jr., 1982; 1986 (Box 15)
  - Kirkwood, James, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Kitto, Humphrey Davey, Findley, 1962-1963 (Box 16)
  - Koschies, Maryjane, 1983-1986; 1991-1994 (Box 16)
  - Kroll, Lucy, 1992 (Box 16)
  - L (Box 16)
  - The Lab Theater, 1996 (Box 16)
  - Lacey, Verna, 1978-1980 (Box 16)
  - Lafotune, Josse, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Lamp, Jere, 1982-2006 (Box 16)
  - Langella, Frank, 1975 (Box 16)
  - Laundra, Linda, See Sileika, Gintare.
  - Lester, Raymond A., 1970-1971 (Box 16)
  - Lawrence, Stephen, 1973 (Box 16)
  - Leonard, Jim, 1996 (Box 16)
  - Levinson, Aaron, 1975-1991 (Box 16)
  - Levinson, Richard
  - Lindsay, Claudette and Werner, 1997-2005 (Box 16)
  - Link, William, See Universal City Studio.
  - Lippa, Sonia, 1977-1985 (Box 16)
  - Lithgow, John, 1982 (Box 16)
  - Living Works, 1995 (Box 16)
  - Litz, Robert J., 1980-1982; 1993,; 1995 (Box 16)
  - Lorant, Stefan, 1975 (Box 16)
  - Los Angeles Independent Film Festival, 1995 (Box 16)
  - Los Angeles Independent Film Festival, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Los Angeles Independent Film Festival, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Lovelace, Margo, 1974-1975 (Box 17)
  - Lowell, Joan, 1991-2001 (Box 17)
  - Ludden, Allen, 1966-1967 (Box 17)
  - Lundquist, Barbara, 1970-1986; undated (Box 17)
  - Lynn, Amy, 1964; 1976 (Box 17)
  - M (Box 17)
  - MacDermot, Galt, 1978-1982 (Box 17)
  - MacDonald, Jane, 1987-1990 (Box 17)
  - Marcus, Deena, 1987 (Box 17)
  - Marcus, Herbert, 1970-1971; 1976 (Box 17)
  - Markey, Mary Jo ("MJ"), 1996-1998 (Box 17)
  - Markson, Edith Sherin, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Martin, Stephen, 1972-2005 (Box 17)
  - Mason, Clifford, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Massie, Sallie, 1973-1975 (Box 17)
  - Mastergeorge, Harry, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Matter, David, 1977-1982 (Box 17)
  - McCarthy, Frank, See Universal City Studio.
  - McClintock, Jodie Lynne, 1986 (Box 17)
  - McDonald, Beth and Nick Wyman, 1978-1981 (Box 17)
  - Medencevic, Suki, 1993 (Box 18)
  - Meyer, Suzanne, 1978-1981; 1998 (Box 18)
  - Michlin, Barry, 1977; 1980,; 1991,; 1994,; 1997 (Box 18)
  - Middlebrook, Diane Woods, 1983-1984; 1991 (Box 18)
  - Miller, Donald, 1977-1978 (Box 18)
  - Miller, J. Michael, 1975-1976; 1982 (Box 18)
  - Miner, Worthington, 1966; 1970 (Box 18)
  - Mon Valley Travel, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Monarch Press, 1966 (Box 18)
  - Moore, Dudley, 1964-2002 (Box 18)
  - Morrow, Helene, 1980-1990 (Box 18)
  - Mosher, Gregory, 1986 (Box 18)
  - Moss, Robert, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Movsesian, Nance, 1965; 1978 (Box 18)
  - MTV Networks, 1996 (Box 18)
  - Myers, Michele, 1998-1999 (Box 18)
  - N (Box 18)
  - Nacht, Milton, 1964; 1966 (Box 18)
  - Nagrin, Daniel, 1960-1997; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Naragon, Maurice and Maggie, 2003-2005 (Box 19)
  - National Endowment For The Arts: Theater Evaluation Program, 1983-1985
    - Administrative and financial (Box 19)
    - Site visits, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - The National Observer, 1973 (Box 19)
  - NationalPlaywrights Conference, See The Eugene O'Neill Theater Center.